残酷な天使のように 少年よ 神話になれ
青い風が今 胸のドアを叩いても 私だけをただ見つめて 微笑んでるあなた
そっとくれるもの 求めることに夢中で 運命さえまだ知らない 痛い気な瞳
だけどいつか気づくでしょう その背中には
遥か未来 目指すための羽があること
残酷な天使の転生 窓辺からやがて到達
もっと走る熱いパッドスで 思い出を裏切るなら
この空を抱いて輝く 少年よ 神話になれ
エリア!
ここにスペシ sol
や take out Curriculum
vastが終わりだ
お前たと一つタイカイの組メントに 厳しい
よいことに話 全体の公斤を迫させやして
Yes, I'm afraid so. Unit 4 is gone, alone with the second branch of nerve.
It happened while they were testing the S2 engine.
But don't worry, we'll be all right.
All three of our Avas are functioning properly, and our pilots and staff are in good shape, too.
I also heard that Unit 3 is being brought here.
You're performing the activation test at Matsushiro, aren't you?
Uh-huh. I'll be out for four days or so, but don't worry.
Akashi's coming over to take care of you guys.
But what about the test?
Oh, Ritsuko will be supervising everything.
There won't be any problems.
And who will be the pilot?
Well, the pilot is...
Yes?
Good morning, Major Katsuragi. I've come to ask for your help.
I'm begging you. Please, please, you've just got to choose me as the pilot for Evangelion Unit 3.
You gotta!
So, Shinji still doesn't know, huh?
I just can't find a chance to tell him. I'm worried. Sometimes I just can't figure out what he's thinking about.
Oh, get a grip, kid. You're the one who wanted to be his guardian.
Yeah, you're right, of course.
Um, so, when will you acquire the new pilot?
Tomorrow. There's still a few details to be ironed out.
Maybe the new pilot will tell Shinji himself.
Oh, no, I rather doubt it. This one wasn't very enthused about the prospect at all. He won't talk. He only accepted under the condition that his younger sister be transferred into our private hospital.
How can Miss Otto be so cruel? I'm dying to be pilot. So why won't she use me, even as a backup pilot? It's just not fair.
Mm-hmm. Yeah.
Hey, what's up? You left before me, but you're getting here late.
Oh, no fight between the newlyweds today?
Ah! I just didn't want to see your ugly faces, you damn three-studious-feduct idiot!
Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow! Ow!
Ah, the precious moment of lunchtime. Hey, where's Toji?
I haven't seen him.
You mean he left? Without his lunch? Toji the stomach? That's impossible!
Hmm. Well, he's been acting different.
Mr. Sousaha?
Huh? Oh, it's you, Ayanami.
Hey, if you're looking for Shinji, he's not here.
You know, don't you, about everything?
I think Asuka knows, too.
Hmm.
So, Shinji's the only one who doesn't know.
You know, it's pretty rare for you to be concerned about someone else.
It is? I'm not sure I understand.
Oh, you have a thing about Shinji, all right.
I?
Maybe that is true.
You do.
Hikari!
Let's have lunch together!
Okay.
He's over two hours late, but last he's finally here.
This is the first time I've ever waited for someone this long.
That's because you never waited for guys back when you could still get a date.
Oh, shut up.
This was the so-called second impact.
At that time, I was living in a place called Nebukawa,
but the rising water levels caused by the melting of Antarctica have buried it beneath the sea.
I'm sorry, newcomer, but I had to clobber you.
I had to beat you to work off my own anger.
Oh, I'm sorry, Asuka. You usually walk home with Shinji, don't you?
I only walk with Shinji because we work together. And right now, I don't be like looking at him.
Oh.
This is about Toji, isn't it?
Yeah. How'd you know?
Everybody knows. The Three Stooges are the only ones who don't.
Shinji seems sensitive in a naive kind of way.
Shinji's a big fat dork. And he's denser than lead, too. He wouldn't know how to relate to another person if you gave him a manual.
Oh, I see.
Asuka, I think that Toji might be interested in Rei.
Are you kidding? Toji and Wonder Girl?
Well, lunch, they seem...
Ha! Don't worry, Hikari. It'll never happen. If Shinji is denser than lead, then Rei Ayanami is off the atomic scale.
Really?
Yup.
Can I ask you something?
Uh, okay.
Just what do you see in a dumb jock like that?
It's the...contentioned sign.
What?
It was a mistake to get back with you.
How can you say that now?
There are a lot of pit holes in life, but you just have to dig your way out.
You know, Asuka...
Kashi sure spends a lot of time in the tub.
I wonder who's going to pilot Unit 3.
What? You mean you haven't heard?
Who is it?
Yes. The only reason I came back to you was so we could break up again.
I don't know.
Yeah, that was refreshing.
Are you two fighting again? I don't believe it. Are you two always like this whenever Katsuragi's gone?
It's not like that. I want to be happy, Kashi, especially since you're spending the night, but I can't. Not tonight. Not now. Not with everything.
I understand. Let's go to bed. I find that's usually the best thing to do in this kind of situation.
Hey, are you asleep yet, Kashi?
No, not yet.
Um, well, can you tell me what my father's like?
Well, there's a surprise question. I would have thought you'd have asked about Katsuragi.
It seems like you're always with my father.
Commander Fuyutsuki is the one who's always with him. Have you been asking around about your father?
I just haven't been around him much.
So, you really don't know him.
But I've learned a lot about him lately.
I've learned how he feels about his work. About my mother.
No, you're wrong, Shinji. You only believe that you've learned.
But people really can't understand themselves, much less each other.
Understanding 100% of anything is impossible.
That's why we spend so much time trying to understand our own motivations and those of others.
That's what makes life so interesting.
So, you can't understand Misato either.
The kanji that we use for the word she means a woman far away.
And women will always seem to be on a distant shore.
The gulf that separates male and female is broader and deeper than any ocean.
I just don't understand adults.
T-minus 300 minutes to Unit 3 activation test.
Primary power standing by.
Repairs to left arm crimp lock completed.
Refrigeration system in all sections function at standard levels.
Roger. Team B, commence operation.
Data link to Avangelion Unit 1 established.
The system's all up and ready for full activation.
Terrific. Let's get started.
That was enthusiastic.
You're aware that this unit will be assigned to your detachment once it's passed its tests, aren't you?
Exclusive control of four Avas.
If you wanted to, you could conquer the world.
So, have you told Shinji yet?
I'll tell him after the test.
The fourth child has arrived. Squad 2, begin entry preparations immediately.
Toji hasn't shown up yet, Asuka.
Yeah, he may not come today.
I thought we might eat together today.
Do you want this?
Unit 3's already arrived in Japan, hasn't it?
Yeah, it got here yesterday.
This sucks. Who's gonna pilot it then?
I told you was absent today. Maybe it's him.
I don't think so.
Entry plug secured.
Initiating burst connection.
Transmitting pulse. Graph readout is normal.
All checklists up to 1350 have been cleared.
Phase 1 contact all cleared.
Roger. Operation will proceed to Phase 2.
Full nerve link established.
Harmonics, level is 1055.
Harmonics are reading standard.
We are now approaching the absolute border.
Break the nerve circuits! Abort the test!
No! Mission failure!
We've got high energy readings in the body!
An angel!
No!
There's been an explosion in Matsushiro!
Damage level unknown.
Send the rescue squad to 3rd Battalion.
We've gotta handle this before the self-defense force gets involved.
Roger!
We've got an unidentified object detected at the site.
Its pattern is orange. We can't confirm that it's an angel yet.
Go to first stage alert.
All personnel, go to first stage alert.
Prepare for surface to surface combat.
All AVAs, prepare for launch.
First for maximum intercept potential.
Air transportation to Matsushiro will go in 20.
An accident in Matsushiro? It can't be!
What happened to Misato?
Contact hasn't been restored yet.
What are we gonna do? We need her.
We're gonna have to go for it ourselves.
There aren't any other options left open for us, are there?
But how can we find an angel without her?
Commandry Curry will command this operation.
My father will?
We're receiving an image of the target from the Nobe Mountain Station.
Transferring to the main monitor.
As we suspected.
Transmit the abort signal.
Eject the unit's entry plug.
It's not working, sir.
Neither the abort or plug ejection codes are being accepted.
What about the pilot?
His heart's still beating and he's still breathing.
But he's probably...
I see.
Then we must accept the loss of Evangelion Unit 3.
Reclassify it as the 13th Angel.
What?
Sir.
Deploy our forces around the base of Mt. Nobe.
The target must be destroyed.
Target is approaching.
All units, prepare to engage.
Huh?
It can't be.
Is that the angel?
No.
Asuka!
Ava Unit 2 has ceased transmitting.
The pilot's ejected. Recovery teams are moving in for retrieval.
Target is moving towards Unit 0's position.
Ray, stop it, but avoid close-range combat.
I'll send Unit 1 in to support you.
Yes, sir.
But the pilot is...
The angel is merging itself into Unit 0's arm!
Nerve contamination spreading!
Sever the left arm immediately.
But the pilot's nerve connections are still active.
Cut it off.
Right.
Unit 0 is heavily damaged. The pilot is wounded.
The target is approaching you, Unit 1.
Contact in 20 seconds. You must destroy it.
But this target isn't just an angel.
There's somebody inside it, isn't there?
Another kid just like me.
Oh, an entry block. I knew it! I knew there was someone in there!
You know what? Life support system's failing!
Pilot life functions are endangered!
Dammit! Cut our pilot's seek ratio down to 60%.
Belay that.
But, but, but, Akari, if we don't, the pilot could be killed.
Shinji, why aren't you fighting?
I can't. There's still a person inside that thing.
Irrelevant. It's an angel. Destroy our enemy.
I can't. If he's alive, I can't.
I can't.
There's still a person inside that thing.
But, but, Akari, if we don't, the pilot could be killed.
Shinji, why aren't you fighting?
I can't.
There's still a person inside that thing.
Irrelevant.
It's an angel.
Destroy our enemy.
I can't.
If he's alive, we've got to help him.
I can't kill another human being.
It's him or you.
No!
I'd rather die!
Dammit.
Shut down all of Unit 1's synchronization circuits immediately.
Shut them down?
Correct switch all control to the dummy plug system, but sir the dummy plug isn't fully operational yet
Dr. Akagi hasn't approved its use. It's still better than the current pilot do it
What's going on
What are you doing father?
Single reception is green
Control system switching is complete
All nerves link to the dummy system thirty two point eight percent of emotional elements are unclear. It can't be monitored
Irrelevant engage the system commence attack
My god, is this what the dummy plug is for gain is still increasing
Thank you
Ugh!
Ah!
Stop it!
Father, stop this goddamn thing, for God's sake!
Please, please, just stop it!
Make it stop!
Stop!
No!
Ava Unit 3, I mean, the target has gone completely silent, sir.
Now what shall I cook?
For Godama, Nozomi, and myself?
But these all serve four.
I sure hope he's hungry tomorrow.
Over here!
There's a survivor here!
Third Squad, erase...
Blockade the entire Highway 20.
Do it now!
Two survivors found each.
Yes, recorder's craft.
Are you alive?
Yes, sir.
Under a header meter.
Roger.
Kaji?
You were lucky, Katsuragi.
Go ahead and link between the roadways...
Where's the freaking skull?
In Koboji Zawa.
Don't worry.
She wasn't hurt as bad as you.
Oh, good.
What about Ava 3?
It was destroyed.
As an angel.
By Unit 1.
I...
I never told Shinji.
It's Shinji.
Shinji?
Misato?
You're...
Okay?
I'm sorry.
God, I'm sorry.
I had to tell you something...
Something important, but...
Oh, dear God, I'm sorry.
Misato...
I...
I killed...
My dad forced me to.
I begged him and begged him, but...
Oh, Shinji.
I'm...
I'm sorry.
Report from the entry plug recovery squad.
The pilot's life signs are confirmed.
He's alive!
Shinji?
The pilot of Unit 3 is...
The fourth...
Child is...
Shinji?
No!
Hot?
vapors playing...
Oh!
No!
Thank you.